A Guide to the George Cary Eggleston Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #6331-a
George Cary Eggleston Collection 1874-1904
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
6331-a
14 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit [1963 Dec 17] 1964 Aug 25
Item Listing
- LETTERS
  - George Cary Eggleston to J. R. Osgood & Company, 1874 Jan 12; ALS, 1 p.
    [Thanks for liberal dealings and promises to repay their courtesy with article on Thomas DeQuincey. ]
  - George Cary Eggleston to Harriet Mann Miller, 1874 Sept 26; ALS, 1 p.
    [Asks her to contribute article to
    American Homes
    magazine.]
  - George Cary Eggleston to Louisa May Alcott, 1874 Oct 7; ALS, 2 p.
    [Discusses type of stories she should write for
    . Detailed description of his plans for
    . Mentions his previous association with
    Hearth and Home
    . ]
  - George Cary Eggleston to [Mary Louise] Booth, 1881 Jun 3; ALS, 2 p.
    [Accepts invitation to meet [Anna Elizabeth] Dickinson. Comments on Virginia's social rules. Passing mention of Edmund Clarence Stedman. ]
  - George Cary Eggleston to "Dear Madam", 1886 Jul 6; ALS, 1 p.
    [Regrets that he cannot attend party for Axel Carl Johan Gustafson and Mrs. Zadel (Barnes) Buddington Gustafson. Passing mention of Edward Eggleston. ]
  - George Cary Eggleston to "My Dear Sir", 1887 Aug 5; ALS, 1 p.
    [States that the
    Commercial Advertiser
    will reprint their interview the following day.]
  - >George Cary Eggleston to John William Weidemeyer, Secretary, 1887 Dec 19; ALS, 1 p.
    [Acknowledges receipt of check from D. Appleton and Company as payment for article on Robert E. Lee in Volume III of the
    Cyclopedia of American Biography
  - George Cary Eggleston to Robert Underwood Johnson, 1888 Oct 18; ALS, 2 p.
    [Thinks he may have made an error in dates in the Cold Harbor sketch. Asks to see a proof of the article. Note: This article was published in
    Leaders of the Civil War
    , Volume 4, p. 230-32, edited by Robert Underwood Johnson. ]
  - George Cary Eggleston to Edmund Clarence Stedman., 1889 Jul 23; ALS, 1 p.
    [Thinks he verified text of Rossiter Raymond's "Cavalry Song" by comparing it to version in Francis Fisher Browne's
    Bugle Echoes
    . Note: a check of Browne's Bugle Echoes reveals that Rossiter Raymond's "Calvary Song" is not contained in it.]
  - George Cary Eggleston to Edmund Clarence Stedman, 1889 Sept 3; ALS, 2 p.
    [Discusses list of great sayings of noted men sent to George Cary Eggleston and William Henry Merrill for review and additions. Notes that the saying attributed to Thomas Gold Appleton was made by George Dennison Prentice. ]
  - George Cary Eggleston to John Nathan Cobb, 1893 Sept 30; ALS, 1 p.
    [States that
    Techumseh
    was written by Edward Eggleston and his daughter, Elizabeth Lillie Eggleston Seelye and published by Dodd, Mead & Company, New York. ]
  - George Cary Eggleston to Edmund Clarence Stedman, 1901 Dec 7; ALS, 4 p.
    [Thanks Edmund Clarence Stedman to the personally inscribed copy of
    "Mater Coronata"
    which he has presented to his son, Cary Eggleston. Comments on his son's literary abilities. Passing mention of the poem,
    "The Lord's Day Gale."
    ]
  - George Cary Eggleston to Carolyn [Melissa Winward], 1904 Jul 3; ALS, 4 p.
    [Discusses problems with the novel,
    A Captain in the Ranks
    . Finds Carolyn Melissa Winward's assistance valuable and will send manuscript to her to copy. Mentions interruptions to his work: headaches, visitors, and his son's marriage on Sept 8. Note: Date of this letter based on dedication of above novel to "Mabel on her wedding day, Sept 8, 1904."]
  - George Cary Eggleston to William [Wallace] Young, n.d.; ALS, 2 p.
    [Explains that his son has not answered the letter in William Wallace Young's behalf because his son has been in upstate New York. Answer due tomorrow will be put in the "y" box at the Author's Club.]